# Peter MoDavis

# Web Developer

#### Peter MoDavis

2677 Braddock Street Philadelphia, PA 19125

Phone: 215-758-1982

Email: pmodavis.webdev@gmail.com
Github: https://github.com/PeterMoDavis

Website: <a href="https://petermodavis.github.io/portfolio/">https://petermodavis.github.io/portfolio/</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-modavis-76346b204/

# **Summary**

Former musician, stay-at-home dad and recent graduate of UPenn Full Stack Bootcamp. Proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git, Bootstrap, Logic Pro X, Pixelmator playing the banjo and much more. Self-learned front end web development for one year prior to bootcamp for a deeper understanding. Has bachelors in English from Temple University.

# Technical

Languages: JS, HTML, CSS

**Frameworks:** Bootstrap, SemanticUI, jQuery, jQueryUI **Concepts:** DRY, API's, Git, Github, Closure, Recursion

Programs: Logic Pro X (audio editing), Pixelmator (image editing)

# **Projects**

#### Weather Dashboard:

https://petermodavis.github.io/weather-dashboard/

Used two calls to two different API's to dynamically present the user with the current weather and the 5 day forecast of the desired city. Utilized Event Delegation to manage the local storage.

#### **Coding Quiz Challenge:**

https://petermodavis.github.io/coding-quiz-challenge/

Created a quiz that presents questions to a user. If the user answers incorrectly then time is taken off the timer that is counting down. Final score can be saved in the users local storage.

#### \_\_\_

# **Experience**

## Family / Stay-at-Home Dad

February 2017 - 2020, Philadelphia, PA

Bathed, fed, played with newborn until she turned three. Made breakfast, lunch and dinner, cleaned diapers, went on playdates and potty trained the child into a fully functional human.

## Savannah Painting/ High-end Interior Painter

June 2010 - February 2017, Philadelphia, PA

Managed and maintained jobs working in Chestnut Hill greatly reducing the burden of the owner painter. Advised customers on complimentary color options and finished the painting of 100 year old houses that sold for upwards of a million dollars.

### Big Man on Campus Publishing / professional musician

MONTH 2003 - Present, Philadelphia PA

Started a publishing company to sell personal works to film and tv. Two songs were featured on Showtime's original series Shameless. Managed a touring band which was well reviewed by the New York Times, Washington Post, Playboy and many others.

# **Education**

## University of Pennsylvania Full Stack Bootcamp

February 2021 - April 2021, Philadelphia, PA

Completed a rigorous full-stack bootcamp focusing on the frontend and backend of web development.

## **Temple University / English**

September 1999 - June 2003, Philadelphia, PA

Graduated magna cumme laude recieving a Bachelors in English with a senior capstone in poetry.